Noah McDonough

Application Developer

211 N Church St #1 Charles Town, WV 25414

571.356.6631

noah@nmcdonough.com www.nmcdonough.com

Skills

I am a highly creative full stack web developer who is proficient in UI design and development. I have worked on webapps using React, various AWS tools, Java JSTL and ticket management systems such as JIRA and AgileCraft. Proficient knowledge of Agile Scrum. Familiar with AWS modules (EC2, ApiGateway, ElasticSearch, Lambda), Angular/React development, Nodejs backend development, Java/JSTL, hibernate, MySQL and NoSQL databases, and a variety of supplementary Javascript packages and libraries.

Experience

Grant Solutions / Application Developer

JANUARY 2019 - AUGUST 2019, ROCKVILLE, MD

Main responsibilities included attending Scrum meetings, maintaining and organization a clean, efficient code source, writing and reviewing code for best practices in Reactjs and Java. As an Application Developer I, I contributed to the Recipient Insight application, a revolutionary app that shows IRS data nobody has ever seen before.

Coding Dojo / Full Stack developer

MAY 2018-AUGUST 2018, VIENNA, VA

A professional office environment for learning and cultivating the skills and understanding required to become a proficient application developer. Applications created in the MEAN, Java and Python stacks.

Scotto's Rigatoni Grill / General Manager

OCTOBER 2014 - APRIL 2018, ASHBURN, VA

As General Manager, I trained and led a team of around 20 people. Focus on customer service and negotiations with local businesses.

Education

Southern Virginia University

SEPTEMBER 2012 - APRIL 2014, BUENA VISTA, VA

I studied Computer Science at a small school in southern Virginia. During my time there I got my first taste of the sometimes grueling experience of programming.

Awards

Triple MVC Certification

- -Pvthon MVC
- -MEAN MVC
- -Java MVC